Mss.Ms.Coll.95 Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Research Subjects (Box 19-85)
  - Iroquoian (Box 32-69)
    - Tuscarora (Box 65-69)
      - The Tuscarora Pronominal Prefixes, 1948-1949; 32 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 67)
        Morphological analysis with discussion and paradigms.
      - Miscellaneous Notes and Texts, 1983, 1987, n.d.; 27 pp (Box 67)
        Includes folder labeled "Hewitt's Tuscarora version of the Seneca Cosmology."; letters to FGL from Blair Rudes; partial text and English translation; and "A Seneca Version."
      - Notes and Chapter Drafts on Tuscarora Grammar, 1973; 89 pages; Mithun, Marianne (Box 67)
      - Word Order in Tuscarora, 1972; 4 pages; Mithun, Marianne (Box 67)
        Handout for 1972 Conference on Iroquois Research.
      - John Napoleon Brinton Hewitt: Tuscarora Linguist, 1994; 1 item; Rudes, Blair A. (Box 67)
        Offprint from Anthropological Linguistics, Vol. 36.
      - Historical Phonology and the Development of the Tuscarora Sound System, 1976, n.d.; 2 items; 2 folders; Rudes, Blair A. (Box 67)
        Copies of two versions of Rudes' dissertation.
      - Tuscarora Dictionary, 1991, n.d.; ca. 900 pages; 9 folders; Rudes, Blair A. (Box 67-68)
        Entries alphabetically by Tuscarora stem, some with English index. Includes letters to FGL, handout "In Search of Meaning" for 1991 Iroquois Conference, table with notes "Tuscarora Aspect Conjugation Classes," and NEH grant proposal.
        - Folder #1 (Box 67)
        - Folder #2 - A-stems (Box 67)
        - Folder #3 - A-stems (Box 67)
        - Folder #4 - C-stems (Box 68)
        - Folder #5 - E-stems (Box 68)
        - Folder #6 - H-stems (Box 68)
        - Folder #7 - I-stems (Box 68)
        - Folder #8 - K-stems (Box 68)
        - Folder #9 - L-, S-, O, and W-stems (Box 68)
      - The Tuscarora Legacy of J. N. B. Hewitt: Materials for the Study of the Tuscarora Language and Culture, 1983-1984; 580 pages; 3 folders; Crouse, Dorothy; Rudes, Blair A. (Box 68-69)
        Letter and photocopy of typed manuscript.
      - J. N. B. Hewitt, 1994; 2 items; Graymont, Barbara; Tooker, Elisabeth, 1927- (Box 69)
        Letter to FGL and photocopy of typed document.
      - Tuscarora/Onondaga, 1991, n.d.; 51 pages (Box 69)
        From FGL's folder: "Tuscarora/Onondaga, Nora Carrier Kenohenyo"-texts, vocabulary, etc.
      - Tuscarora Vocabulary, n.d.; 7 pages (Box 69)
        Photocopy, from unidentified source, of table labeled "Lawson's History of North Carolina."
  - Kinship (Box 69-76)
    - Australia, n.d.; 25 pages (Box 69)
      Handwritten notes and diagrams; typed manuscript by D. Wilson.
    - Batak Kin Classification and Behavior, 1966-2006 (Box 69)
      Accession M2008-02.
      Gift of Harold Scheffler, 16 February 2008.
      Documents the proceedings and results of a graduate school seminar on the structural analysis of systems of Toba Batak kin classification and behavior, held at Yale University, February - May 1966.
      - 1. Index (Box 69)
      - 2. Kinship Term Diagrams (Box 69)
      - 3. Notes on Queries and Analysis (Box 69)
      - 4. Seminar Transcripts, Sessions 1-3, February 11-25, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 5. Seminar Transcripts, Sessions 4-6, March 4-18, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 6. Seminar Transcripts, Sessions 7-9, April 8-15, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 7. Seminar Transcripts, Sessions 10-12, April 19-26, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 8. Seminar Transcripts, Sessions 13-15, April 28 - May 6, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 9. Seminar Transcripts, Sessions 16-18, May 10-17, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 10. Candalin Data and Interpretations, Part One, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 11. Candalin Data and Interpretations, Part Two, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 12. Wolfart Data and Analyses, Part One, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 13. Wolfart Data and Analyses, Part Two, 1966 (Box 69)
      - 14. "Analysis of the Batak Kinship System", 1967; Kokot, Daisy Hilse (Box 69)
      - 15. "Toba Batak Kin Classification: A Preliminary Formal Analysis", May 1977; Taylor, Paul M. (Box 69)
      - 16. PDF files - Lounsbury Lectures (Box 69)
        PDF files contained on a CD-R disk.
    - El protosistema de parentesco Maya: una tentativa de reconstruccion, n.d.; 45 pages; Borodatova, A. A., (Anna A.); Kozhanovskaya, Irina (Box 70)
      Photocopies of two versions of the paper. From a bundle of papers labeled: "Maya kinship unfin. project."
    - Kinship Systems and Inverse Semigroups, 1972; 48 pages; Boyd, John Paul, 1939-; et al (Box 70)
      Mimeo of typed manuscript with photocopies of handwritten additions and diagrams. From a bundle of papers labeled: "Maya kinship unfin. project."
    - Breton, n.d.; 35 pcs. (Box 70)
      Although identified as Breton, most of the contents of FGL's folder pertain to Island Carib and other languages.
    - Cherokee, n.d.; 6 pages (Box 70)
      Notes on kinship terms.
    - Chiricahua (Apache), n.d.; 6 pages (Box 70)
      Ditto of handwriten manuscript giving terms, analysis, and a chart.
    - Codex Madrid, n.d.; 11 pages (Box 70)
      Photocopy of typed manuscript. pertaining discussing hieroglyphs from page 33b of the Codex. From a bundle of papers labeled: "Maya kinship unfin. project."
    - Cree, n.d.; 41 pcs. (Box 70)
      Kinship terms with notes.
    - Crow-Omaha, n.d.; ca. 200 pages; 3 folders (Box 70)
      Handwritten and typed drafts of paper on kinship.
    - Dani, 1969, n.d.; ca. 30 pcs. (Box 70)
      Kinship terms, analysis, handwritten notes etc. Material may be from Denise O'Brien's dissertation, "The Economics of Dani Marriage: ..." From a folder "Kofyar" (which see).
    - Nomenclature et structure de parente des indiens Tzeltal, 1962, 1963; 3 items; Robles Uribe, Carlos; Sousberghe, Leon de (Box 70)
      Offprint and photocopy from L'Homme, vol. 2, and photocopy of "Nomenclature et structure de parente des Maya du Yucatan d'apres les sources anciennes (Motul, Beltran)," L'Homme, vol. 3 From bundle: "Maya kinship unfin. project." From envelope: "ks: Colonial Yucatec."
    - Fox, n.d.; 8 pages (Box 70)
      Diagrams and analysis.
    - An Evolutionary Sketch of Russian Kinship, 1962; 27 pages; Friedrich, Paul, 1927- (Box 70)
      Offprint from Symposium on Language and Culture: Proceedings of the 1962 Annual Spring Meeting of the American Ethnological Society.
    - Genealogical Diagram, n.d.; 1 page (Box 70)
      Blank form.
    - Gilyak, 1933, 1957, 1963, 1971, n.d.; 6 items (Box 70)
      Handwritten notes; photocopy of pages from L. Ya. Shternberg, "Sem'ya u rod u narodov cebero-vostochnoj Azii" (in Russian); offprint of Roman Jakobson, "Notes on Gilyak," Bulletin of the Institute of History and Philology, Academia Sinica, Vol. XXIX; translation of Takeshi Hattori, "Gilyak Kinship Terms," Anthropology Tomorrow, Vol. 9; Lydia T. Black, "Relative Status of Wife Givers and Wife Takers in Gilyak Society," paper delivered at the NE Anthropological Association.
    - Delaware Kinship Terminology, 1973; 1 item; Goddard, R. H. Ives, III (Box 70)
      Offprint from Studies in Linguistics, Vol. 23.
    - Fox (Mesquakie) Kinship Terminology, 1992, n.d.; 2 items; Goddard, R. H. Ives, III (Box 70)
      Photocopy of typed manuscript. Includes letter from Goddard to FGL.
    - Greek, 1965; 1 item (Box 70)
      "The kin Terminology of Classical Greek Including a Discussion of ??????S"-by Ted O'Leary.
    - Hawaii, n.d.; 33 pages (Box 70)
      Various typed and handwritten notes on Hawaiian and Polynesian kinship terms.
    - Hebrew, 1955; 14 pages (Box 70)
      Arnold Jacob Wolf, "Primary Kin-types in Hebrew"-term paper for FGL's Linguistics 222.
    - The Indo-European Kinship System, 1928; 1 item; Hocart, A. M., (Arthur Maurice), 1884-1939 (Box 70)
      Photocopy of article from Ceylon Journal of Science, Vol. 1.
    - Hopi, n.d.; 38 pages (Box 70)
      Floyd G. Lounsbury, "A Formal Account of Hopi Kinship Terminology"-handwritten draft; C. F. and F. M. Voegelin, "The Autonomy of Linguistics and the Dependence of Cognitive Culture"-preprint of article to appear in Festschriften for Claude Levi-Strauss, et al.
    - Classic and Modern Relationship Terms and the "Child of Mother" Glyph (T I:606.23), [1986]; 1 item; Hopkins, Nicholas A. (Box 70)
      Photocopy of article to appear in Sixth Palenque Round Table. From a bundle of papers labeled: "Maya kinship unfin. project."
    - Kalmuk, n.d.; 34 pages (Box 70)
      Analysis and discussion of kinship terms in Kalmuk Mongol; notes from Aberle 1953. From folder: "Maxwell-Kalmuk.
    - Kamba, 1951, n.d.; 15 pages (Box 70)
      Notes on kinship terms; letters to FGL from Bob Dentan and unidentified party; draft letter from FGL to Dentan. From folder: Kambe-"Dentan."
    - Kapauku, n.d.; 35 pcs. (Box 70)
      Notes and typed draft on kinship terms of Kapauku of the Kamu Valley.
    - On Quibblings over Squabblings of Siblings: Some Reflections on Kin Terms and Behavior, 1 item; Keesing, Roger M., 1935- (Box 70)
    - Kofyar, n.d.; 18 pages (Box 70)
      Notes and analysis.
    - Kinship Terminology and Linguistic Structure, 1965; 1 item; Lamb, Sydney M. (Box 71)
      Photocopy of abstract of paper for Super-Conference for Anthropologists.
    - Latin Kinship, 1964-1965, n.d.; 28 pages (Box 71)
      Notes, analysis, and a handout.
    - Latin Thesaurus, 1958, n.d.; ca. 125 pages (Box 71)
      Photocopy primarily of the index.
    - Theory of Groups of Permutations, Matrices and Kinship, 1968; 1 item; Liu, Pin-hsiung (Box 71)
      Offprint from The Bulletin of the Institute of Ethnology, Academia Sinica, No. 26.
    - The Constitution of Kinship, n.d.; ca. 40 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 71)
      Notes and partial draft. From folder: "Book Plan 'Essays on the Constitution of Kinship'."
    - Distinctive Features of Kinship Systems, n.d.; 33 pp and 4 test booklets; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 71)
      Typed and handwritten notes and partial drafts. Includes typed drafts of "The Componential Structure of the Iroquois-type Kinship System" (draft for ICAES, Philadelphia) and lists of "Seneca Consanguineal Classes." Most items from folder: "Iroq. Ks.-Old versions."
    - Expressions of Relationship in Iroquoian, 1976, n.d.; 1 page; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 71)
      Typed handout for talk to Yale Linguistics Club. From folder: "Seneca Kinship."
    - A Formal Account of the Crow- and Omaha-Type Kinship Terminologies, 1964, n.d.; 2 items; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 71)
      Offprint from Explorations in Cultural Anthropology: Essays in Honor of George Peter Murdock, and a photocopy of a published French translation.
    - On the Exploitation of Kinship Terminologies in Social Anthropology, n.d.; ca. 20 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 71)
      Draft, bibliographies, course reading lists, etc. From folder: "Bibliographies Ks-Essay on-".
    - The Problem of Determinants in Kin-Group Organization, n.d.; 13 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 71)
      Typed draft and notes.
    - Review of Rodney Needham's Structure and Sentiment: A Test Case in Social Anthropology, 1962, n.d.; ca. 185 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 71)
      Notes, drafts, carbon copy, corrections sent to Edward H. Spicer, ed. of American Anthropologist; offprint AA, Vol. 64.
    - A Semantic Analysis of the Pawnee Kinship Usage, 1956, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 71)
      Annotated offprint from Language, Vol. 32 with notes in margins and on additional sheets. From folder: "Rethinking Pawnee" and "Pawnee revision."
    - The Structural Analysis of Kinship Semantics, 1961, 1964, n.d.; ca 100 pp; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 71)
      Notes, typed and handwritten drafts, etc. From folders: "I.C.L. Paper" and "Seneca Kinship." Also includes an offprint from Proceedings of the Ninth International Congress of Linguists, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1962.
    - The Structure of the Latin Kinship System and its Relation to Roman Social Organization, 1967; 18 pages; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 71)
      Photocopy from VIIme Congres International des Sciences Anthropologiques et Ethnologiques, Moscow, 1964, Vol. 4.
    - Symbols of Kinship, n.d.; ca. 30 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 71)
      Notes, draft. From folder: "Texas paper-symbols of ks."
    - Manus and Arunta, 1 p (Box 71)
      Diagrams comparing the two systems.
    - Maya Kinship Analyses, n.d.; 18 pages (Box 71)
      Short analyses done by FGL's students. From bundle: "Maya kinship unfin. project."
    - Maya Kinship Notes, 1966, n.d.; ca. 75 pp, and 32 3x5 cards (Box 71)
      Notes, photocopies, student work. From bundle: "Maya kinship unfin. project."
    - Measures of Kinship Distance, n.d.; 5 pages (Box 71)
      From folder: "Measures of kinship distance, with diagrams (from early draft of Pawnee paper)."
    - Notes on the Piegan System of Consanguinity, 1916; 1 item; Michelson, Truman, 1879-1938 (Box 71)
      Offprint from Holmes Anniversary Volume. Marked with rubber stamp: "Leo J. Frachtenberg, Bureau of American Ethnology, Washington, D.C."
    - Miscellaneous Charts, n.d.; 5 pages (Box 71)
      Charts showing Crow and weak Omaha systems. From folder: "Charts for J. O. talk."
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1954, 1956, n.d.; 57 pages; 2 folders (Box 71)
      Includes: 2 pages of "The Determinants of Kinship Terminology"; several copies of "Seneca Consanguineal Classes"; Pawnee kinship terms from Morgan's "Republican Pawnee"; letter to FGL from Zdenek Salzmann regarding his proposed study of Arapaho kinship; Squamish kinship terms; letter to FGL from [illegible] re study of Squamish; "Chou China" kinship chart; note to FGL from Dorothy Ester with copies of diagrams for publication; quotes from published works; preliminary draft.
    - Mixe-Zoquean Kinship Terminology, n.d.; 22 pages (Box 71)
      Typed manuscript. giving terms, meaning, and some discussion. From bundle: "Maya kinship unfin. project."
    - Mnong Gar, n.d.; ca. 125 items; 2 folders (Box 72)
      Notes, analysis, drafts regarding kinship system of the Mnong Gar (Vietnam).
    - Motul Data, n.d.; ca. 50 pcs. (Box 72)
      Kinship terms and analytical notes.
    - Omaha Type Charts, n.d.; 5 pcs. (Box 72)
      Charts showing Omaha types I through IV.
    - Onitsha (Igbo D.), n.d.; 12 pcs. (Box 72)
      Data and analysis.
    - Papers calling for reply, 1962, 1966, 1968, n.d.; 8 items, 23 pcs. (Box 72)
      Offprints and drafts of articles on kinship analysis; draft responses.
    - Parental Substitute, 1972, n.d.; 26 pages (Box 72)
      Notes on kinship; draft of "A Problem in the Description of Elementary Social Structures: The Parental Substitute."
    - Pawnee, n.d.; 72 pcs.; 3 folders (Box 72)
      Notes and analysis of Pawnee kinship terms. Two groups from folders: "Weltfish data" and "Pawnee: Lesser; Dorsey, Murie,Spoehr; Morgan."
    - Prosopographica, 1963; 24 pages; Peel, J. D. Y., (John David Yeadon) (Box 72)
      Photocopy of handwritten manuscript. A discussion of Latin names in the Roman Empire.
    - Punjabi, n.d.; 3 pages (Box 72)
      List of Punjabi kinship terms.
    - Purum, 1945, 1958, 1961, 1964, 1965; 5 items and ca. 65 pages; 2 folders (Box 72)
      The Purums: An Old Kuki Tribe of Manipur and photocopies of pages missing from FGL's copy; offprint of George L. Cowgill's brief communication from AA, Vol. 66 regarding Charles Ackerman's criticism of Rodney Needham's analysis; offprints or Rodney Needham's "A Structural Analysis of Purum Society," David B. Eyde and Paul M. Postal's "Avunculocality and Incest: The Development of Unilateral Cross-Cousin Marriage and Crow-Omaha Kinship Systems," and FGL's "Another View of the Trobriand Kinship Categories" (AA Vols. 60, 63, and 67); notes and drafts for a talk by FGL. APS folder #2 from folder: "FGL-Purum-in progress. NY Acad."
    - Two Formal Analyses of Lacandon Mayan Kinship Terms, 1 item and 10 pages; Rees, Michael J. (Box 72)
      Paper done for FGL. From bundle: "Maya kinship unfin project." From folder: "Yucatec kinship."
    - Kinsmen and Friends in Zuni Culture: A Terminological Note, 1965; 1 item; Roberts, John M. (Box 72)
      Offprint from El Palacio. From bundle: "Maya kinship unfin project."
    - Russian, 1954, n.d.; 37 pages (Box 72)
      Two papers by Paul W. Friedrich, "The Kinship Terminology of the Great Russian Peasant" (a term paper) and "Componential Analysis and Russian Kinship."
    - Further Comments on "Kinship and Cognition", 1986; 22 pages; Scheffler, Hal W. (Box 72)
    - Seneca, 1859, 1889, 1988, n.d.; 5 items and 6 loose sheets (Box 72)
      Includes: letter to FGL from Betty [Elisabeth Tooker]; kinship terms from L. H. Morgan; kinship terms from Caroline G. Parker and I.Newton Parker; notes and references.
    - Seneca and Cayuga Kinship Terms, ca. 50 pcs. (Box 72)
      Kinship terms with English translation and analysis. Most items from folder: "Seneca Kinship."
    - Serbo-Croatian and Rumanian, 1965, n.d.; 10 pages (Box 72)
      Includes lists, charts, and a map.
    - Shukla, Shaligram. Kinship System in Panini's Astadhyayi, n.d.; 1 item; Shukla, Shaligram (Box 72)
    - Slavic, n.d.; 22 pcs. (Box 72)
      Typed carbon of ms. on Slavic kinship terms "...from a linguistic point of view." From folder: "Trubachev."
    - South America (Box 73-75)
      - Esposos, Suegros y Padrinos entre los Aymaras, 1972; 1 item; Albo, Xavier (Box 73)
        Draft of paper for discussion in the symposium on Andean kinship and marriage, AAA, Toronto.
      - Apinaye (Apinage), 1966, n.d.; 66 pages (Box 73)
        Handwritten draft manuscript and notes, mimeograph handout, and photocopies of published references-analysis of the kinship system.
      - Apinaye (Apinage) Data Sheets, n.d.; ca. 80 slips (Box 73)
        Handwritten notes on the analysis and meaning of kinship terms.
      - Apinaye (Apinage) Paper, n.d.; ca. 80 pages (Box 73)
        FGL's typed drafts of "Parallel Descent, the Apinaye 'Anomaly' and Dr. Maybury-Lewis's Interpretation." Includes handwritten notes and partial draft.
      - Apinaye Notes, n.d.; ca. 200 pcs. (Box 73)
        Notes, analysis, drafts on Apinaye kinship. From folder: "Apinaye."
      - Aymara Kinship Terminology, n.d.; 8 pages (Box 73)
        16th Century Terminology from Bertonio and Torres Rubio-photocopy of typed document
      - Myths and Legends and Traditions of Lambayegue, 24 pages; Barrandiar Leon, Agusto (Box 73)
        Translations of stories from Myths and Legends and Traditions of Lambayegue-typed manuscripts.
      - Bibliography, n.d.; 48 slips (Box 73)
        References regarding Inca kinship.
      - Tawanku: Intercouple Bonds in a Qolla Village, 1973; 1 item; Bolton, Ralph (Box 73)
        Ditto of paper presented at AAA, New York.
      - Kinship and Land Use in a Northern Sierra Community, 1972; 1 item; Brush, Stephen B. (Box 73)
        Ditto of paper presented at the symposium on Andean kinship and marriage, AAA, Toronto.
      - Canella, 1976-1978, 1984, n.d.; ca. 240 pcs.; 2 folders (Box 73)
        Notes, analysis, charts, drafts, correspondence, etc. regarding Canella kinship. From folders: "Canella-FGL" and "Canella-."
      - Peasant Kinship, Subsistence and Economics in a High Altitude Andean Environment, 1972; 1 item; Custred, Glynn (Box 73)
        Photocopy of typed paper presented at the symposium on Andean kinship and marriage, AAA, Toronto.
      - On Andean Kinship, 2 items; Earls, John (Box 73)
        Typed unsigned letter discussing his work.
      - Gramatica y Arte Nueva de la Lengua General de todo el Peru, llamada Lengua Qquichua, o Lengua del Inca. Lima, 1607, n.d.; 57 pages; Gonzalez Holguin, Diego, b. 1552 (Box 73)
        Photocopies of several pp. regarding kinship terms. Includes analysis and partial English translation. Used in FGL's paper "Some Aspects of the Inca Kinship System."
      - Guajiro, 1957, 1981, n.d.; 4 items and ca. 70 pages (Box 73)
        Handwritten and typed draft and notes on Guajiro kinship. Offprints of: Jean-Guy Goulet, "The Guajiro Kinship System: Its Semantic Structure and Social Significance" (bound with Ives Goddard, "Against the Linguistic Evidence Claimed for Some Algonquian Dialectal Relationships"), Anthropological Linguistics, Vol. 23, 1981; Johannes Wilbert, "Verwandtschaftssystem der Goajiro", Zeitschrift fur Ethnologie, Vol. 82, 1957; Johannes Wilbert, "Kinship and Social Organization of the Yekuana and Goajiro", Southwestern Journal of Anthropology, Vol. 14, 1958.
      - KUYAQ: Those Who Love Me: An Analysis of Andean Kinship and Reciprocity Within a Ritual Context, 1972; 1 item; Isbell, Billie Jean (Box 73)
        Photocopy of paper presented at the symposium on Andean kinship and marriage, AAA, Toronto.
      - Formal and Sociological Analysis of Ramkokamekra Kinship, 1964, n.d.; 120 pages; Keesing, Roger M., 1935- (Box 74)
        Typed and ditto versions of paper on kinship system of the language also known as Canella (northeastern Brazil). Includes four letters between Keesing and FGL.
      - The kinship terminology of the Piro, Eastern Peru, 1974; 1 item; Baer, Gerhard, 1934-; Loffler, Lorenz G. (Box 74)
        Offprint from Ethnologische Zeitschrift Zurich.
      - Algunos Aspectos del Sistema de Parentesco Inca, n.d.; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 74)
        Spanish translatin of FGL's paper from Tinkuy, Universidad del Cuzco, Peru.
      - Aspects du systeme de parente Inca, 1978; 1 item; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 74)
        Photocopy of French translation of FGL's paper, Annales economies Societes Civilisations, Nos. 5-6 including "Bibliographie generale."
      - Miscellaneous Notes on Inca Kinship System, 1963, n.d.; 157 pcs.; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 74)
        Notes, analysis, draft, etc. in preparation of his paper "Some Aspects of the Inca Kinship System."
      - Notes on Inca Kinship, n.d.; ca. 300 slips; 4 folders; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 74)
        5" x 8" slips with notes on numerous kinship terms from various sources.
      - Some Aspects of the Inca Kinship System, 1978, n.d.; ca. 320 pp; 3 folders; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn (Box 74)
        Several copies and versions of the paper deliverecd in Barcelona; 2 offprints and 1 photocopy of "Aspects du systeme de parente Inca" from Annales economies Societes Civilisations.
      - Tape of Lecture Given at the University of California [Los Angeles] on Inca Kinship, n.d.; 58 pages; [Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn] (Box 74)
        Handouts, notes, analysis, and photocopy of the talk.
      - Kin, Compadres, Padrinos and Comuneros in Cusipata, 1972; 1 item; Malengreau, Jacques (Box 74)
        "Kin, Compadres, Padrinos and Comuneros in Cusipata: a contemporary village of the Peruvian Andes"-photocopy of typed paper presented at the symposium on Andean kinship and marriage, AAA, Toronto.
      - Arte de la Lengua General del Peru llamada Quichua, 1584, n.d.; 24 pages; [Martinez Oramechea, Juan] (Box 74)
        Photocopies of selected pages. Used in FGL's paper "Some Aspects of the Inca Kinship System."
      - Miscellaneous Translations of Works on Andean Marriage Customs, 6 pages (Box 74)
        English translations of materials from unspecified works.
      - Notes from Juan de Betanzos and Pedro Gutierez de Santa Clara, 19 pages (Box 74)
        Used in FGL's paper "Some Aspects of the Inca Kinship System."
      - El hombre y la familia, su matrimonio y organizacion politico-social en Q'ero, 1957; 1 item; Nunez del Prado C., Oscar (Box 74)
        Pamphlet published by Universidad Nacional del Cuzco.
      - Ritual Formulario, e Institucion de Curas, para administrar a los Naturales de este Reyno, los santos sacramentos. Lima, 1631, 40 pages; Perez Bocanegra, Juan (Box 75)
      - Succession, Cooption to Kingship, and Royal Incest Among the Inca, 1960; 1 item; Rostworowski de Diez Canseco, Maria (Box 75)
        Offprint from Southwestern Journal of Anthropology, Vol. 16, No. 4.